

Vancouver, Canada

+1-604-418-1985 • alecng94@gmail.com alecng.ca • linkedin.com/in/alecng • github.com/alec-ng

Professional Summary

Frontend software engineer with 3.5 years industry experience in web application development, technical architecture, and business consulting. Delivered multiple SaaS based solutions used by over 50,000 users as a tech lead responsible for the full development lifecycle. Expertise lies in combining a technical foundation in modern frontend development practices with strong interpersonal skills to deliver innovative user experiences.

Skills

Front-End: React, ES6 JavaScript, Redux, Node.js, Jest, Enzyme, HTML5, CSS3, Webpack

Back-End: Google Firebase, NoSQL/Relational Databases, SQL, Salesforce Apex (Java-inspired OOP Language)

DevOps: Git, Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD), GitHub Actions

Software Practices: Test Driven Development (TDD), Behaviour Driven Development (BDD), Agile Methodology

Client Service: Product Demos, Business Presentations, Requirement Gathering

Work Experience

Groundswell Cloud Solutions

Senior Technical Consultant

Jan 2019 - Oct 2019

- Facilitated the technical design of a customer portal intended to serve 600,000 users across 3 continents by leading client facing software architecture sessions on security, scalability and data migration strategies
- Led the implementation and release of a mobile app feature deployed to over 13,000 users by performing code reviews, organizing sprints, and handling deployments as the developer lead in a team of 6
- Spearheaded the formalization of the company's development security standards based on OWASP and Salesforce guidelines, resulting in the company's standardization of project security testing
- Developed excellent communication and time management skills from working in a partial remote capacity alongside colleagues and clients operating in different time zones

Technical Consultant Sep 2017 - Jan 2019

- Created the front end UI, UX, and architecture for a customer portal launched to 40,000 active users by transforming designer mockups to HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Fostered a 1.5 year long relationship with a client where I acted as the principal point of contact, led the delivery of two front end applications, and created future project roadmaps
- Selectively chosen to present a 20 minute talk to over 200 people at Dreamforce 2018, Salesforce's annual user conference, about JavaScript testing on the Lightning Platform

Delivered a public facing Google Maps JavaScript application to a client that logged an average of 8,000 unique searches a day

Technical Consultant Co-op

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016

- Published a Salesforce managed package written in JavaScript that improves developer productivity by providing versioning capabilities for Salesforce's Wave Analytics dashboard application
- Supported the development and release of a custom Salesforce integrated subscription system, enabling the client to track payments made through Stripe for their 300 person user base

Cardant, formerly Avanti Commerce

Software Engineer Co-op

May 2015 - Dec 2015

- Optimized an internal PDF exporting tool by converting it from a server to client side JavaScript application, achieving a 75% reduction in wait time
- Refactored an ASP.NET test suite following Agile methodology, resulting in a 20% increase in code coverage

Projects

React Library | react-brandywine-editor

Jan 2020

- Created an open source block editor library using React and JavaScript that allows the user to create custom web blogging content with a drag and drop interface
- Leveraged GitHub Actions tooling to automate build processes and package publishing to npm, where it has been downloaded 500 times

React Application | alecng.ca/blog

Nov 2019

- Launched a hiking blog which uses React Hooks for the front end and Firebase for providing authentication, hosting, and a NoSQL database
- Created a custom CMS system that integrated a NoSQL database with a React/Redux application to create, manage, and publish blog posts

Education

Bachelor of Applied Sciences, Computer Engineering, 2017 University of British Columbia Academic Distinction